Have you ever found yourself watching a trashy film on an aeroplane, tears welling up as the cheesy crooner sings its theme song?
你有没有发现自己在飞机上看一部蹩脚电影时，随着蹩脚的流行歌手演唱主题曲而热泪盈眶？
I certainly have.
我当然有过。
And I’m not alone.
而且不止我一个人这样。
So much so that Virgin Atlantic recently released a list of the films that cause people to cry the most.
以至于维珍大西洋航空公司最近发布了一份最让人落泪的电影名单。
Get this: 7% of people admitted to crying during the sad parts, while 10% owned up to getting emotional at happy endings.
听听这个：7%的人承认在悲伤情节时哭过，而10%的人承认在幸福结局时情绪激动。
What is it about being 35,000 feet up in the air that causes such heightened emotions?
在35000英尺的高空，是什么导致了如此强烈的情绪呢？
So, what’s going on?
那么，这是怎么回事呢？
How does air travel tap into our hidden emotions?
乘坐飞机旅行是如何触动我们隐藏的情感的呢？
A study from the Netherlands has shown adults cry due to feelings of separation, loneliness or powerlessness.
荷兰的一项研究表明，成年人会因为分离、孤独或无力感而哭泣。
All of these are easily experienced when flying: you‘re far from family, often alone, and have no control over the aircraft’s flight.
在飞行时，这些感受都很容易体会到：你远离家人，常常独自一人，而且无法控制飞机的飞行。
Another theory relates to the lack of distraction.
另一种理论与缺乏分散注意力的事物有关。
When you‘re strapped into your seat in a sealed cabin in the sky, there’s not a lot you can do.
当你被捆绑在天空中一个密封的客舱里的座位上时，你能做的事情并不多。
So we are able to invest ourselves more fully into the movies we watch.
所以我们能够更全身心地投入到我们所看的电影中。
Then there‘s the physical space.
然后是物理空间的因素。
Air pressure and oxygen levels are lower, and this can affect our mental state.
气压和氧气含量较低，这会影响我们的精神状态。
Conditions in an aeroplane resemble those at an altitude of 2,400m.
飞机内的环境类似于海拔2400米处的环境。
The reduced oxygen at this height can affect the brain.
在这个高度氧气含量的降低会影响大脑。
According to a study by the US Institute of Medicine: “the initial mood experienced at altitude is euphoria, followed by depression.”
根据美国医学研究所的一项研究：“在高海拔地区最初的情绪体验是兴奋，随后是抑郁。”
And what about the movies themselves?
那么电影本身呢？
Virgin say top culprits include tearjerkers such as Billy Elliot, Eat Pray Love and, at number one position, Toy Story 3.
维珍航空公司表示，最让人落泪的电影包括《跳出我天地》、《美食、祈祷和恋爱》，排名第一的是《玩具总动员3》。
Their emotional firepower even caused the aeroplane to slap tongue-in-cheek “emotional health warnings” on select movies back in 2011.
这些电影的情感冲击力甚至使得航空公司在2011年对某些电影半开玩笑似的贴上了“情感健康警告”。
Virgin Atlantic film critic Jason Solomons said at the time, “On a flight, we‘re isolated, leaving loved ones or aching to be reunited with them.
维珍大西洋航空公司的影评人杰森·所罗门斯当时说：“在飞行途中，我们与世隔绝，离开了所爱的人，或者渴望与他们团聚。
We’re nervous, we‘re tired, we might have had a drink at a time we usually wouldn’t, and if we see an image, a scene that reflects our emotional state, frankly we‘re suckers.
我们紧张、疲惫，我们可能会在平时不会喝酒的时候喝上一杯，如果我们看到一个画面、一个反映我们情感状态的场景，坦率地说，我们就变成容易被骗的傻瓜。
Flying and films is a heady cocktail.
坐飞机看电影就像喝了一杯令人陶醉的鸡尾酒。”